<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.8.3">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2018-07-14T12:21:54+10:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/</id><title type="html">Gabriel Dwyer</title><subtitle>Hello, World</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Welcome to Jekyll!</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/jekyll/update/2018/07/11/welcome-to-jekyll.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Welcome to Jekyll!" /><published>2018-07-11T14:30:50+10:00</published><updated>2018-07-11T14:30:50+10:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/jekyll/update/2018/07/11/welcome-to-jekyll</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/jekyll/update/2018/07/11/welcome-to-jekyll.html">&lt;p&gt;You’ll find this post in your &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;_posts&lt;/code&gt; directory. Go ahead and edit it and re-build the site to see your changes. You can rebuild the site in many different ways, but the most common way is to run &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;jekyll serve&lt;/code&gt;, which launches a web server and auto-regenerates your site when a file is updated.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To add new posts, simply add a file in the &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;_posts&lt;/code&gt; directory that follows the convention &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;YYYY-MM-DD-name-of-post.ext&lt;/code&gt; and includes the necessary front matter. Take a look at the source for this post to get an idea about how it works.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jekyll also offers powerful support for code snippets:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-ruby&quot; data-lang=&quot;ruby&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;def&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nf&quot;&gt;print_hi&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;name&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;puts&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&quot;Hi, &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;si&quot;&gt;#{&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;name&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;si&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&quot;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;end&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;print_hi&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;'Tom'&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;c1&quot;&gt;#=&amp;gt; prints 'Hi, Tom' to STDOUT.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Check out the &lt;a href=&quot;https://jekyllrb.com/docs/home&quot;&gt;Jekyll docs&lt;/a&gt; for more info on how to get the most out of Jekyll. File all bugs/feature requests at &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/jekyll/jekyll&quot;&gt;Jekyll’s GitHub repo&lt;/a&gt;. If you have questions, you can ask them on &lt;a href=&quot;https://talk.jekyllrb.com/&quot;&gt;Jekyll Talk&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">You’ll find this post in your _posts directory. Go ahead and edit it and re-build the site to see your changes. You can rebuild the site in many different ways, but the most common way is to run jekyll serve, which launches a web server and auto-regenerates your site when a file is updated.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Heroism, Leadership, and Batman</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2015/05/04/Heroism-Leadership-and-Batman.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Heroism, Leadership, and Batman" /><published>2015-05-04T13:48:00+10:00</published><updated>2015-05-04T13:48:00+10:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2015/05/04/Heroism-Leadership-and-Batman</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2015/05/04/Heroism-Leadership-and-Batman.html">&lt;p&gt;I have an enduring love for superheroes. They’re your ‘Average Joe’ with a secret, latent gift that makes them exceptional, exciting and amazing individuals. They have super-human, super-natural and super-cool skills. Not only that, they’re practically immortal!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[embed]https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=vHm2XrwpGtI[/embed]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;© College Humor&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Superheroes have an intoxicating appeal upon all of us. From modern stories (Harry Potter, Beatrix Kiddo) to ancient legends (Heracles, Robin Hood), heroes are worshipped by humanity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Admittedly, a complex hero. © Miramax
We hold these individuals up as shining examples of people giving their all, and using their gifts to help serve the ‘greater good’. The hero’s story, of overcoming personal problems, powerful adversaries and trying to find their place in a complex world, is incredibly compelling.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Joseph Campbell theorised the existence of a ‘monomyth’ (Campbell 1949) relating to just this, stating that much of art, culture and story follows the basic plot of a hero. A natural progression: a hero’s “call to adventure”, defeat and subsequent “initiation”, followed by the “return” of the hero to defeat his/her ultimate challenge. Of the transfixing nature of this story, Campbell states:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;The happy ending of the fairy tale, the myth, and the divine comedy of the soul, is to be read … as a transcendence of the universal tragedy of man.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;(Campbell 1949)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The hero is deeply imbedded and idolised within our cultural psyche. But does this aid, or distract us from our beliefs about leadership?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If superheroes really are as awesome as they seem, perhaps that is the ideal we should aim for. With the aid of superpowers, we’ll solve all the world’s problems and live in a utopia by next week.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But (assuming you’re alright with the whole secret identity thing), there’s just one problem with that. The superhero’s story never ends. No matter whom they defeat, the cycle constantly continues. And, for good reason…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[embed]https://youtu.be/5-BLS7WlyQo[/embed]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;© Disney/Pixar&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let us consider the most realistic superhero of them all; Batman. He is a shining example of leadership, dedication and honour, with bountiful intelligence, wealth and resourcefulness to make up for his lack of supernatural powers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Despite the endless nights spent gallivanting around Gotham City, fighting crime and global threats, back they come.  And Arkham Asylum remains the penitentiary with the highest turnover I’ve heard of.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Why can’t the Caped Crusader create lasting and fundamental change in Gotham? Because he has fallen victim to the largest misconceptions of systems and leadership prevalent today: the illusion of the broken system (Heifetz, Grashow &amp;amp; Linksy 2009), and the hero complex (Sonnenfeld 2015).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bruce Wayne first became Batman as a response to the inadequacy and corruption of the Gotham Police Force. In a crime-ridden city, he attempted to build a better future. However, as Heifetz, Grashow and Linksy, suggest:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;There is no such thing as a dysfunctional organisation, because every organisation is perfectly aligned to achieve the results it currently gets.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;(Heifetz, Grashow &amp;amp; Linksy 2009)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Superficially, it appears that The Dark Knight is attempting to ‘fix’ the broken justice and police systems of Gotham, but this simply cannot be true. All those who have the power to affect the crime rates of Gotham have accepted the current results of the system, despite how dysfunctional it may appear. Plus, something of the eccentricity of Batman led to a surge of maniacal, costumed villains. For realists (Inspector Gordon), Batman is a menace, actually &lt;em&gt;contributing&lt;/em&gt; to the problem of crime, rather than fixing it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Wayne’s espoused values of justice, protection and selflessness are not matched by his actions. If he were truly aiming to reduce crime, he would use his considerable influence as a businessman to tackle the causes, including poverty, insufficient education and social discrimination (Weatherburn 2001). Instead, he fulfils a selfish desire for personal heroics, and Gotham rewards him for it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What a leader would do. Image credit: courtesy of generator © Thomas Hunter. https://thomashunter.name/
Alfred had it right, bless his soul. Gotham does not need the Dark Knight. Gotham needs the builder, the philanthropist, the human. Bruce Wayne.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By far, the saddest scene of The Dark Knight Rises (2012). Image credit: http://wegotthiscovered.com/movies/michael-caine-confims-alfred-bruce-wayne-dark-knight-rises
The prevalence and idolisation of heroics within our culture has created a dangerous precedent for leadership.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Heroes are a conservative force, preserving the status quo. Rather than addressing the adaptive challenge before them, they addressing the symptoms without diagnosing the cause, and refuse to acknowledge their contribution to the mess. They are foolish, irresponsible and remain consciously ignorant, claiming the moral high ground to prevent open and progressive debate.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Government initiatives, social enterprises, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.projects-abroad.org/volunteer-projects/building/&quot;&gt;volunteer groups&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&quot;http://fortune.com/2015/02/02/hero-complex-leadership/&quot;&gt;leaders&lt;/a&gt; must ask conflictual questions of themselves if they are to have any hope of thriving in spite of, and ultimately defeating the problems they align themselves against.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;#∑&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Heroism is a dangerous trap, prioritising self-fulfilment over the needs of the many.  To be a leader, one must hang up their cape, cowl, and boots, and develop progress by addressing the core of an issue. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;References.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">I have an enduring love for superheroes. They’re your ‘Average Joe’ with a secret, latent gift that makes them exceptional, exciting and amazing individuals. They have super-human, super-natural and super-cool skills. Not only that, they’re practically immortal!</summary></entry></feed>